FELIPE TAHA SANT'ANA, Ph.D.

+48-882-844-704 | ftahas@proton.me | ftahas.github.io

in ftsantana | 🖸 ftahas | 🎔 ftsantan | 📵 ORCID | G Scholar

Introduction

I am a theoretical physicist with experience in academia and background on interacting quantum systems, integrable models, quantum field theories, mathematical physics, and AMO physics in general. Currently, I am a Polonez Bis fellow at the Institute of Physics, Polish Academy of Sciences, working on integrable quantum field theories in one dimension under the project CIQS: Correlation aspects of Interacting Quantum Systems in reduced dimensionality.

EDUCATION

• University of São Paulo

04/2020

Ph.D. in Physics São Carlos, Brazil

- Keywords: Bose gases, optical lattice, quantum phase transition, 1d interacting systems.
- Thesis: A study on quantum gases: bosons in optical lattices and the one-dimensional interacting Bose gas. arXiv:2006.13100; teses.usp

University of São Paulo

07/2015

M.Sc. in Electrical Engineering

São Carlos, Brazil

- Keywords: Autonomous robots, dynamical environments, collision probability estimation.
- · Dissertation: Estimação de probabilidade de colisão com obstáculos móveis para navegação autônoma. teses.usp

University of São Paulo

07/2012

B.Sc. in Physics São Carlos, Brazil

EXPERIENCE

Institute of Physics, Polish Academy of Sciences []

11/2022 - 10/2024

Assistant Professor

Warsaw, Poland

- NCN Polonez Bis 1 Fellow
- Principal Investigator of the project CIQS: Correlation aspects of Interacting Quantum Systems in reduced dimensionality
- Faculty of Physics, University of Warsaw [

10/2020 - 09/2022

Assistant Professor

Warsaw, Poland

- Postdoctoral researcher within the NCN Sonata project "Dynamic correlation functions of quantum integrable models: in and beyond the equilibrium" headed by Miłosz Panfil.
- Institut de Physique de Nice, Universit
 è Côte D'Azur []

06/2018 - 05/2019

Ph.D. Researcher

Nice, France

- Doctoral researcher under CAPES/COFECUB bilateral collaboration.
- São Carlos Institute of Physics, University of São Paulo []

04/2016 - 04/2020

Ph.D. Researcher

São Carlos, Brazil

- Doctoral researcher within project "Bose gases in optical lattices" headed by F.E.A. dos Santos.
- Luz Financial Solutions []

2015

Financial Analyst

São Carlos, Brazil

São Carlos School of Engineering [)

03/2013-07/2015

M.Sc. Researcher São Carlos, Brazil Master student within the project "Dynamic environments in autonomous robotics" headed by Valdir Grassi Jr.

Warthog Robotics [\(\phi \)]

2012-2013

AI Developer São Carlos, Brazil

TEACHING

Quantum Field Theory

2023-2024

Institute of Physics, Polish Academy of Sciences

Warsaw, Poland

Lecture notes

• Statistical Physics

2021-2022 Warsaw, Poland

Faculty of Physics, University of Warsaw

2021-2022

Quantum Mechanics

Faculty of Physics, University of Warsaw

Warsaw, Poland

Computational Physics

2017

São Carlos Institute of Physics, University of São Paylo

São Carlos, Brazil

PROJECTS

- CIQS: Correlation aspects of Interacting Quantum Systems in reduced dimensionality November 2022 October 2024 Keywords: Quantum Field Theories, Integrable models, 1d interacting systems
 - Project No. 2021/43/P/ST2/02904 co-funded by the National Science Centre and the European Union Framework Programme for Research and Innovation Horizon 2020 under the Marie Skłodowska-Curie grant agreement no. 945339.

PUBLICATIONS

C=CONFERENCE, J=JOURNAL, P=PATENT, S=IN SUBMISSION, T=THESIS

- [J.1] Oleksandr Gamayun, Miłosz Panfil, Felipe Taha Sant'Ana, Kubo-Martin-Schwinger relation for an interacting mobile impurity, Phys. Rev. Research 5, 043265, 2023. arXiv:2308.06482
- [J.2] Oleksandr Gamayun, Miłosz Panfil, Felipe Taha Sant'Ana, Mobile impurity in a one-dimensional gas at finite temperatures, Phys. Rev. A 106, 023305, 2022. arXiv:2202.07657
- [J.3] Miłosz Panfil, Felipe Taha Sant'Ana, The relevant excitations for the one-body function in the Lieb-Liniger model, J. Stat. Mech. (2021) 073103. arXiv:2104.10491
- [T.1] Felipe Taha Sant'Ana, A study on quantum gases: bosons in optical lattices and the one-dimensional interacting Bose gas, University of São Paulo thesis repository arXiv:2006.13100
- [J.4] F. T. Sant'Ana, F. Hébert, V. Rousseau, M. Albert, P. Vignolo, Scaling properties of Tan's contact: Embedding pairs and correlation effect in the Tonks-Girardeau limit, *Phys. Rev. A* **100**, 063608 (2019). arXiv:1908.08714
- [J.5] Felipe Taha Sant'Ana, Axel Pelster, and Francisco Ednilson Alves dos Santos, Finite-temperature degenerate pergutbation theory for bosons in optical lattices, *Phys. Rev. A* **100**, 043609 (2019). arXiv:1906.09661
- [J.6] M. Kübler, F. T. Sant'Ana, F. E. A. dos Santos, and A. Pelster, Improving mean-field theory for bosons in optical lattices via degenerate perturbation theory, *Phys. Rev. A* **99**, 063603 (2019).arXiv:1804.08689
- [C.1] Felipe Taha Sant'Ana et al., Warthog Robotics Team Description Paper 2012, Latin American Robotics Competition Symposium (2012).

TALKS AND POSTERS

	10 11 1 2022
Correlation aspects of interacting quantum systems in one dimension	10-14 July 2023
International Conference on Statistical Physics - SIGMAPHI 2023, Chania, Greece	
Correlation aspects of interacting quantum systems in reduced dimensionality	December 2022
BEC seminar, CFT PAN, Warsaw, Poland	
• The relevant excitations for the one-body function in the Lieb-Liniger model	20/02 - 04/03, 2022
São Paulo School of Advanced Science on Quantum Fluids and Applications, São Carlos, Brazil	
Correlation features of interacting bosons	October 2021
Condensed matter physics seminar, FUW, Warsaw, Poland	
Understanding the important excitations in the Lieb-Liniger model	April 2021
Student workshop on integrability, 2021, Hannover, Germany	
• A study on quantum gases: bosons in optical lattices and the interacting Bose gas	December 2020
Condensed matter physics seminar, FUW, Warsaw, Poland	
Bosons in optical lattices	30/01 - 10/02, 2017
School on Interaction of Light with Cold Atoms, São Paulo, Brazil	

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Fortran, C++, Python, HTML, Julia
- Systems and softwares: Linux, LaTeX, Mathematica, MatLab
- Languages: Portuguese (Native), English (Professional Proficiency), Spanish (Intermediate), Polish (Basic)